<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Marc Duclusaud&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Marc Duclusaud&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Megabot</title>
      <link>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/megabot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/megabot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What is the Megabot? The Megabot is a large quadrupedal robot capable of carrying a passenger, primarily designed to be showcased at robotics-related events. It weighs approximately 250 kg, measures around 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dymaxion Globe</title>
      <link>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/dymaxion_globe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/dymaxion_globe/</guid>
      <description>Fuller&amp;rsquo;s Projections The Fuller&amp;rsquo;s projections  are cartographic projections of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s map onto regular polygonal surfaces. Applied in 1946 to a cuboctahedron and in 1954 to an icosahedron, these projections are called the Dymaxion map, from dynamic maximum tension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pneumatic artificial muscles</title>
      <link>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/muscle_artificiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/muscle_artificiel/</guid>
      <description>Principle Pneumatic artificial muscles, also known as McKibben muscles, are actuators comparable to biological muscles, the principle of which was proposed in the 1950s by Joseph McKibben. They are capable of contraction, meaning that when activated, they change from an initial resting elongation to a reduced elongation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand Table</title>
      <link>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/sandtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcdcls.github.io/projects/sandtable/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The goal of this project is to build a coffee table featuring a mechanism that enables the creation of geometric patterns in sand using a steel ball. This sand table is inspired by similar projects such as this one or this one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
